Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "S"
  - STODDARD, CHARLES WARREN, 1843-1909, 3 (Box 27, Folder 1029-1031)
    - Expectation. Autograph ms poem of 5 stanzas, signed with initials
  - STODDARD, ELIZABETH, 1823-1902 (Box 27, Folder 1032)
    - 2 ALS to Stephen Bull French, Sag Harbor and New York, 1901 July, September
    - ANS to Mrs. French, n. p., undated [1901]
  - STODDARD, JOHN L. (JOHN LAWSON), 1850-1931 (Box 27, Folder 1033)
    - 4 ALS to James Young, Merano, Italy, 1902-[1903]
      22 pages
      With a calling card, and three colored views of the Italian lakes Gift of James T. Babb, 1962
  - STODDARD, LORIMER, 1864-1901 (Box 27, Folder 1034)
    - 3 ALS, with addressed envelopes, to Stephen Bull French, Sag Harbor and Liberty, 1899-1901
  - STONE, MARY AMELIA (BOOMER) (Box 28, Folder 1035)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Murray Hill Hotel, May 30
  - STONE, WILLIAM L. (WILLIAM LEETE), 1792-1844 (Box 28, Folder 1036)
    - ALS to Joshua A. Spencer, New York, 1843 August 22
      Matthiessen fund
  - STOREY, VIOLET ALLEYN (Box 28, Folder 1037)
    - ALS to Miss Mary A. Jordan, Brooklyn, 1927 October 18
  - STORY, JOSEPH, 1779-1845 (Box 28, Folder 1038)
    - Letter to Asa O. Aldis, Washington, 1832 February 15
      Removed from: the Aldis copy of v. 1, of his "Life and letters," Boston, 1851
    - ALS. Cambridge, 1839 August 8
      Recommending Robert Hyatt as a lawyer
      Removed from: his Life and letters, Boston, 1851
  - STORY, WILLIAM WETMORE, 1819-1895, 2 (Box 28, Folder 1039-1040)
    - ALS to Miss Foley, Rome, Italy, 1866 February 28
      Alvord fund, October. 1967
    - ALS to Charles E. Norton, Rome, 1862 January 9
      Removed from: His Roba di Roma, London, 1863
    - ALS to Mr. Underwood, Rome, 1890 March 5
      Removed from: His Fiammetta... Boston and New York, 1886 [i. e. 1885]
    - ALS. Rome, 1875 June 6
      Removed from: His Nero...Edinburgh and London, 1875
    - ALS. Rome, 1892 November 26
      Removed from: His Poet's portfolio, Cambridge, 1894
    - O Filia Pulchra. Autograph ms of 5 stanzas
      Removed from: His Poems, Edinburgh, 1885
    - ALS. Rome, 1885 January 19
      Concerns Julian Hawthorne's book on Nathaniel Hawthorne
      Removed from: Phillips, Mary Elizabeth. Reminiscences of William Wetmore Story ...1897
    - ALS. Palazzo Barbarini, Rome, 1878 June 1
      4 pages inset on sheet
    - Autograph signature
      Complimentary close, cut from a letter
  - STREET, ALFRED BILLINGS, 1811?-1881 (Box 28, Folder 1041)
    - ALS to R. B. B. Coffin, Albany, 1852 December 16
      Removed from: His Poems, 1845
    - ALS to George R. Graham, Albany, 1851 August 5
      Removed from: His Drawings and tintings...1844
    - ALS to John W. Francis [and others on the committee for the Knickerbocker Gallery], Albany, 1853 December 24
  - STREET, JULIAN, 1879-1947 (Box 28, Folder 1042)
    - 3 TLS to Gilbert Troxell, Lakeville, Conn., 1943 April, May
  - STRINGER, ARTHUR, 1874-1950 (Box 28, Folder 1043)
    - The Shadow: ms copy, possibly in his handwriting, with signature. Decorative headpiece. Written - or mimeographed - on card
  - STRODE, MURIEL (Box 28, Folder 1044)
    - ALS to Julia Ellsworth Ford, New York, 1923 August 1
      Gift of Julia E. Ford, March, 1951
  - STROTHER, DAVID HUNTER, 1816-1888 (Box 28, Folder 1045)
    - ALS to Mary Townsend (Taylor) Aldis, n. p., 1879 April 9
      Removed from: Za copy of Kennedy,
      The Blackwater Chronicle, New York, 1853
  - STUART, RUTH MCENERY, 1856-1917, 2 (Box 28, Folder 1046-1047)
    - 2 ALS to [Charles G. Bartlett], n. p., undated
    - 2 ALS to Henrietta C. Bartlett, New York, [1895], 1895
    - ALS to Mr. McGee, New Orleans, La., 1915 May 11
      Removed from: her The Story of Babette (1894), on the Alvord fund
  - STURM, JUSTIN C. (Box 28, Folder 1048)
    - 3 ALS to James T(inkham) Babb, Westport, Conn., 1928-1934
  - SULLIVAN, FRANK, 1892-1976 (Box 28, Folder 1049)
    - The Cliché Expert Testifies on Radio Advertising. Typewritten ms signed by the author
  - SULLIVAN, T. R. (THOMAS RUSSELL), 1849-1916 (Box 28, Folder 1050)
    - ALS to Miss (Abby Langden) Alger, 10 Charles St., [n. p.], February 8
  - SUTHERLAND, DONALD (Box 28, Folder 1051)
    - ALS to Carl Van Vechten, Charleston, S. C., 1939 October 1
      Gift of Mr. Van Vechten, November 1942
- "T"
  - TAFT, LORADO, 1860-1936 (Box 28, Folder 1052)
    - TL to Miss Leila Mechlin, [n. p.], 1926 June 18
      With typed signature
      Gift of Walter Pforzheimer, January. 13, 1961
  - TAPPAN, WILLIAM B. (WILLIAM BINGHAM), 1794-1849 (Box 28, Folder 1053)
    - ALS to Charles Cist, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1829 June 3
      Requesting that a special meeting be called of the Cincinnati Sunday School Union
      Purchased on the Kennedy fund, February. 1968
  - TARKINGTON, BOOTH, 1869-1946, 3 (Box 28, Folder 1054-1056)
    - Tarkington, Susanah, 1870-1966. TLS to James T(inkham) Babb, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1936 May 25
      Written on behalf of Booth Tarkington
    - TLS to Bernhard Knollenberg, Indianapolis, 1942 December 20
    - 3 ANS to Charles Parsons, Indianapolis, 1939, 1940
    - TNS with ms postscript to Charles Parsons, Kennebunkport, 1939 October 13
    - 2 TLS to Charles Parsons, Kennebunkport, Maine, 1940 August 8, 13
      [Snapshot of whale laid in]
      Gift of Mr. Parsons, August 1940
    - TNS to Charles Parsons, Kennebunkport, 1940 August 30
      Gift of Mr. Parsons, September 1940
    - TNS to Charles Parsons, Indianapolis, [Ind.], 1941 February 4
  - TATE, ALLEN, 1899-, 2 (Box 28, Folder 1057-1058)
    - TLS to Bernard Knollenberg, Washington, D. C., 1943 October 2
      With carbon copy of Mr. Knollenberg's reply, October. 22, 1943
    - 3 ALS to Louis Lohr Martz, Sewanee, 1944 November, December
      3 leaves, one with envelope
  - TAYLOR, BAYARD, 1825-1878, 5 (Box 28, Folder 1059-1063)
    - AMS of his "Ode to Shelley," six stanzas dated, 1848 September 10
      Removed from: Za copy of his A book of romances, lyrics and songs, Boston, 1852
    - In Winter: original ms of poem, signed with initials, and dated, 1860 June 11
      Seven 4-line stanzas
      [Removed from: Za copy of his Poet's Journal, Boston, 1863]
    - 2 ALS to E. P. Whipple, New York, 1851, 1878
      Removed from: Za copy of his Rhymes of travel, New York, 1849, and of his Prince Deukalion, Cambridge, 1878
    - ALS to C. A. Dana, Bay of Jedo, Japan, 1853 July 17
      Removed from: Za copy of his Visit to India, China and Japan, New York, 1855
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, New York, 1854 July 31
      Removed from: Za copy of his A journey to Central Africa, New York, 1854
    - 3 ALS to William Henry Kilby, New York, 1855-1856
      2 pages, 1 page, and 2 1/2 pages, respectively
      Removed from: Za copy of his Poems of the Orient, Boston, 1855, of his Poems of home and travel, Boston, 1855, and of his Life and letters, v. 1
    - ALS to J. T. Fields, Washington, 1862 March 31
      Removed from: his Hannah Thurston, New York, 1863
    - ALS to Lippincott and Co. (firm, publishers, Philadelphia), Cedarcroft, Kennett Square, Pa., 1866 April 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his Story of Kennett, New York, 1866
    - ALS to W. Reid, Faroe Islands, 1874 July 28 [or 26]
      Removed from: Za copy of his Egypt and Iceland, New York, 1874
    - ALS to Charles Marseilles, New York, 1875 May 10
      2 pages, with original addressed envelope
      Removed from: Za copy of his Echo club, New York, 1895
    - ALS to W. J. Linton, New York, 1877 January 21
      Removed from: Za copy of his Home ballads, Cambridge, 1882
    - ALS to T. W. Higginson, Kennett Square, Penna., 1877 August 14
      Removed from: Za copy of his Echo club, 1876
    - 2 ALS to Mrs. A. C. Lynch-Botta, New York, 1878 January 18, 28
      2 1/2 pages and 2 pages respectively
      Removed from: Za copy of his National ode, Boston, 1877, and of his Victor Emmanuel memorial, New York, 1878
    - ANS to [Calvin G. Child], Kennett Square, Pa., 1858 November 11
      Kingsley Trust Assn, November. 1945
    - ALS [to Dr. Joseph P. Thompson], Berlin, 1878 June 11
      Received from the estate of Dr. Joseph P. Thompson, June 1928
    - Autograph, Madison, 1859 March 2
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," [New York, ], 1855 December 1
    - ALS to Henry Peters Gray, Jr., Mankato, Minn., 1874 November 28
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Kennett Square, Pa., 1870 March 25
      Addressed to the Secretary of a Society in San Francisco of which Gov. Haight was Secretary in 1859
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Kennett Square, Pa., 1871 November 24
    - 2 ALS to James R(ipley) Osgood, Kennett Square, Pa. and Friedrichroda, Germany, 1872, 1878
    - ALS to H(enry) W(ebster) Parker, New York, 1850 April 28
      Parker, a poet, apparently English; author or editor of Poets' Reveille
    - ALS to Gibson Peacock, Kennett Square, Pa.
    - ALS to "My dear Sir," Baltimore, Md., 1856 January 7
      Letter concerns lecture to be given by Taylor
      Acquired on exchange (from German Lit. Coll.), November. 1967
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Omaha, Neb., 1874 December 6
  - TAYLOR, PRENTISS, 1907- (Box 28, Folder 1064)
    - Happy Birthday to Carlo, 1950. Ms booklet illustrated by author in color
      [15] p. mounted port.
      For Carl Van Vechten's birthday, 1950
  - TERHUNE, ALBERT PAYSON, 1872-1942 (Box 28, Folder 1065)
    - 1 AL (in the hand of Mrs. Terhune), 10 TLS, 1 telegram, and 1 typed postcard signed to Robert Williams, Pompton Lakes, N. J., 1927-1940
      With 2 TLS to Mr. Williams from Mr. Terhune's secretary and 2 ALS to him from Mrs. Terhune
      Purchased May 1966 on Danford Barney Fund
  - THANET, OCTAVE, 1850-1934, 3 (Box 28, Folder 1066-1068)
    - Autograph inscription signed, Cataumet, 1890 August 10
    - The Object of the Federation, Setting typescript
      26 leaves
      With a few ms corrections by the author and with printer's marks Signed "Octave Thanet" [1901] with a later note: "This was published in the August Scribner's 1901... Alice French (Octave Thanet)... Clover Bend, Ark., April 23, 1902." Bound in case with an ALS to Mr. Young, giving him the ms, dated Clover Bend, Ark., April 8, 1902. 2 pages
      Gift of Philip M. Neufeld, 1961 in honor of Mr. and Mrs. Max Balkind
    - ANS to Miss Anna C. Fry, Clover Bend, Ark., 1893 February 13
      Signed: Octave Thanet (pseud.)
      Removed from: Za copy of her Knitters in the sun...Cambridge, 1887
    - Autograph, signed "Octave Thanet," Clover Bend, Ark., 1897 December 11
      With an original drawing
  - THAXTER, CELIA, 1835-1894, 3 (Box 28, Folder 1069-1071)
    - Autograph [ms] of her poem "Courage," 7 four-line stanzas on 2 leaves
      Removed from: Za copy of her Poems, 1896
    - ALS to J. R. Osgood, n. p., April 7
      Removed from: her Stories and poems, 1895
    - ALS to "Dear Friend," Newton, April 23
      1 1/2 pages
      Removed from: her An island garden, 1894
    - Autograph [ms] of her poem "By the roadside," 13 four-line stanzas, written on 4 leaves
      Ms note at end: "from Whittier sale,
      March 6, 1903"
    - [Words to an old song by Shields, author unknown; copied in ms by Mrs. Thaxter; two 4-line stanzas on 1 leaf]
      Removed from: Za copy of her Drift-weed, 1879
    - ALS to "Dear Madam," Appledore, 1889 June 24
      Removed from: Za copy of her Letters, 1895
    - ALS to E. P. Whipple, Northrop House, 1883 December 30
      1 1/2 pages (2 leaves)
      Removed from: Za copy of her Among the Isles of Shoals, 1873
    - ALS to Mrs. Rice, Gambrel Cottage, 1878 October 8
      Removed from: her Verses [1891]
    - ALS to Miss Abby Alger, Newtonville, 1871 January 30
      1 1/4 pages (1 leaf)
      Removed from: Za copy of her Poems, 1872
    - 2 autograph four-line stanzas beginning "Remember this. Not all the wild," signed and dated, 1890
      Removed from: the Za copy of her Poems, Cambridge, 1874
    - 2 ALS to W. J. Linton, Appledore and Shoals, 1875 July 9, 13
      2 pages, 1 page
      Removed from: her Poems for children, 1884
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, [Isles of] Shoals, 1888 October 9
      Gift of Mr. and Mrs. E. A. Prentis, from library of Russell Pruden
    - 4 ALS to Clara Anthony, Portsmouth, N. H.; Shoals, 1890-1892
      From the Reed papers, transferred from the Coe Collection, August, 1951
    - ALS to the Rev. George Bainton, Appledore, Isles of Shoals, 1888 April 19
      Answering a request for an autograph
    - ALS to Mrs. Alexander, Appledore, Isles of Shoals, 1867 May 12
      Matthiessen fund, 1958
    - Vesper Song. AMS
      Three 5-line stanzas
      Purchased from Morton with others, 16 November 1960, Alvord and GBF funds
      used
    - ALS to "Dear friends," Hotel Clifford, 1887 January 11
  - THAYER, STEPHEN HENRY, 1839-1919 (Box 28, Folder 1072)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, and Tarrytown, 1899, 1903
      3 leaves with 1 envelope
  - THOMAS, AUGUSTUS, 1857-1934, 3 (Box 28, Folder 1073-1075)
    - The Harvest Moon. Typescript (carbon)
      143 leaves
      In 4 folders
    - The Harvest Moon. Typescript (original)
      47 leaves
      Act I only
    - The Harvest Moon. Typescript (carbon)
      Act III only
    - TLS to Mrs. Helen S. Woodruff, Producing Managers' Association, New York, 1923 March 3
  - THOMAS, EDITH MATILDA, 1854-1925, 3 (Box 28, Folder 1076-1078)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, 1886 January 25
      [Removed from: Za copy of her Fair Shadow Land, 1893]
    - ANS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, West New Brighton, [1895] February 25
      [Removed from: Za copy of her Lyrics and Sonnets, 1889]
    - ANS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, West New Brighton, [1902 April 6]
      [Removed from: Za copy of her In the Young World, 1896]
    - The Heart Upon the Sleeve, ms copy of poem with her signature
    - ALS to Mrs. (Anne Charlotte) (Lynch) Botta with drawing of home, Geneva, Ohio, 1881 January 12
      5 pages (3 leaves attached)
    - ALS to Miss Smith, Geneva, Ohio, 1884 November 13
    - Art in a Sordid Age: ms copy in her hand, with her signature
      Includes: Signature on a card
  - THOMAS, ISAIAH, 1749-1831 (Box 28, Folder 1079)
    - ALS to Hudson and Goodwin (firm, publishers, Hartford), Worcester, Mass., 1797 May 15
      With address overleaf, franked by Thomas as postmaster
  - THOMPSON, MAURICE, 1844-1901, 5 (Box 29, Folder 1080-1084)
    - Founded on a Rock: original ms of essay, with the author's signature on final page
    - When My Dream Comes On: original ms of poem, signed by the author
    - Sappho's Apple: original ms of poem, with the author's signature
    - ANS to Mr. Black, Crawfordsville, Ind., 1887 September 15
    - ALS to Mr. Stoddart, Crawfordsville, Ind., 1892 April 18
    - 3 ALS to Herbert Stuart Stone, Crawfordsville, Ind., 1894 June-July
      4 pages, 2 pages, 2 pages
    - ALS to Dr. Ward, Crawfordsville, Ind., 1891 June 10
      Removed from: Aldis copy of his Witchery of archery (1878)
    - 19 ALS to Henry Chandler Bowen, Crawfordsville, and Indianapolis, Ind., and Bay St. Louis, Miss., 1885-[1895]
    - Alice of Old Vincennes. Typescript (original)
      21 leaf
      Act IV only
    - ALS to Mr. (Henry Chandler) Bowen, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1888 September 18
    - ALS to R(ichard) W(atson) Gilder, Bay Saint Louis, Miss., 1892 March 7
      With a pencil note by W. Carey stating that the letter concerns a poem "Love's horizon," the first line of which is identical with one by Carey written five years earlier but unpublished
    - ALS to Colonel (Thomas Wentworth) Higginson, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1892 November 12
    - ALS to C(harles) W(ells) Moulton, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1894 December 19
    - ALS to Messrs. Stone and Kimball, Crawfordsville, Indiana, [1894]
      Acknowledges statement for Lincoln's Grave (published 1894)
    - ALS to Miss Ward, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1897 February 22
  - THOMSON, CHARLES WEST, 1798-1879 (Box 29, Folder 1085)
    - The American Eagle [poem]. Autograph ms
      "The foregoing verses were composed ...in...1829, and were first published in the Atlantic Souvenir for 1830. This copy was made in July, 1839, for Mr. L. I. Cist, by the author, who now (May 1, 1865)...adds his signature... at his present residence in York, Pennsylvania. C. W. Thomson"
  - THOMSON, MORTIMER (Box 29, Folder 1086)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, 1900 September 14
  - THORBURN, GRANT, 1773-1863 (Box 29, Folder 1087)
    - ANS to Friend McComb, Newhaven, 1860 October 20
      Gift of James H. Penniman, May 11, 1921
  - THORPE, THOMAS BANGS, 1815-1878 (Box 29, Folder 1088)
    - ALS to Benjamin P(erley) Poore, New Orleans, La., 1865 March 1
  - THURBER, JAMES, 1894-1961 (Box 29, Folder 1089)
    - The Whip-Poor-Will: original [ms] written in pencil, and signed with initials on final page
      88 pages
      Gift of B. P. O. Elks no. 25, New Haven - June 1945
  - TICKNOR, GEORGE, 1791-1871, 3 (Box 29, Folder 1090-1092)
    - ALS to Dr. J(acob) Bigelow, Brookline, Mass., 1867 August 4
    - ALS to Miss Legaré [Boston], 1843 November 15
      On p. 4 of ALS from his wife to Miss Legaré, 4 pages
      Removed from: His History of Spanish literature...1849, v. 1
    - ALS to Jean Humbert, Goettingen, Germany, 1816 January 25
      Including address leaf
  - TICKNOR AND FIELDS (Box 29, Folder 1093)
    - Statement of their account with Donald Grant Mitchell, Boston, 1864 August 18
  - TOLAND, M. B. M. (MARY BERTHA MCKENZIE), 1825?-1895 (Box 29, Folder 1094)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, San Francisco, 1879 January 11
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Santa Monica, Cal., 1888 March 7
    - On Receiving His Picture. Autograph ms of poem signed and dated, 1888 March 7
      Originally enclosed with letter to E. C. Stedman, March. 7, 1888
  - TORREY, BRADFORD, 1843-1912 (Box 29, Folder 1095)
    - ALS to Mr. Barton, Melrose Highlands, Mass., 1887 October 12
      Removed from: His Birds in the bush ...Boston, 1885
    - 4 ALS to E. H. Goss, Melrose Highlands and Wellesley Hills [Mass.], 1888-1901
  - TOTTEN, MARY HOWE (Box 29, Folder 1096)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1904, 1905
      2 leaves with 2 envelopes
  - TOURGÉE, ALBION WINEGAR, 1838-1905 (Box 29, Folder 1097)
    - ALS to General Horatio C. King, [n. p.], 1884 March 18
  - TOWNE, CHARLES HANSON, 1877-1949 (Box 29, Folder 1098)
    - ANS to John Kendrick Bangs, [n. p.], 1912 May 20
      Removed from: His Manhattan,, 1909
  - TRAIN, ARTHUR CHENEY, 1875-1945 (Box 29, Folder 1099)
    - ANS to Charles N. Baxter, [New York, ], 1945 July 15
      [Written on postal card]
      Gift of Mr. Baxter, May 1946
  - TRAUBEL, HORACE, 1858-1919 (Box 29, Folder 1100)
    - ALS to Bolton Hall, Philadelphia, Pa.
  - TRIGG, EMMA GRAY WHITE (Box 29, Folder 1101)
    - TLS to Carl Van Vechten, Richmond, Va.
      Gift of Carl Van Vechten, October 1942
  - TRILLING, LIONEL, 1905-1975 (Box 29, Folder 1102)
    - [George Orwell and the Politics of Truth]. Typescript with ms corrections. With a TLS to C. B. Tinker, 11 April 1952, concerning the essay
      21 numbered leaves
      Gift of Mr. Trilling, April, 1952
  - TROUBETZKOY, AMÉLIE RIVES, 1863-1945
    See: RIVES, AMÉLIE, 1863-1945
  - TROWBRIDGE, J. T. (JOHN TOWNSEND), 1827-1916, 3 (Box 29, Folder 1103-1105)
    - ALS to Editors of the Independent, Geneva, Switzerland, 1890 April 14
      Removed from: His My own story... Boston and, 1903
    - ALS to Mr. H. H. Kohlsaat, Arlington, Mass., 1895 April 26
      Removed from: His Martin Merrivale, Boston, 1854. pt. 1
    - ALS to Ticknor, Arlington, 1878 January 10
    - ALS to Elbridge Henry Goss, Arlington, Mass., 1903 December 23
    - ANS to Miss Sanborn, Arlington, 1901 May 2
    - ALS to Dr. [William Hayes] Ward, Arlington, Mass., 1900 June 24
    - ANS to Karl Knortz, Arlington, Mass., 1880 September 27
    - ANS to the Editors, North American [R]eview, Arlington, Mass., 1906 October 9
    - ALS to Wilder [?] D(wight) Quint, Arlington, April 1
      Removed from: Alvord copy of his Poetical Works (B & NY, 1903), 1 of 50 copies uncut
    - 2 ALS to (James Ripley) Osgood, Arlington, Mass., 1876 January 28, February 5
      Alvord fund, October. 1967 (with another to Stoddard)
    - ALS to (Charles Warren) Stoddard, Arlington, Mass., 1904 September 25
      Recipient identified as C. W. Stoddard on basis of contents of letter (Stoddard was living in Cambridge, with friends, in 1904. See D. A. B.)
      Alvord fund, October. 1967 (with 2 others)
    - ALS to Mr. Clarke, Arlington, Mass., 1897 September 28
    - ALS to Mr. (Jesper) Harding, St. Paul, Minn., August 8
      Ltr refers to the Inquirer, edited
      by Jesper Harding
    - ALS to George (Brinton McClellan) Harvey, Arlington, Mass., 1907 November 14
    - 2 ALS to Robert Underwood Johnson, Arlington, Mass., 1897 April 16, 25
      The first letter has a pencil note by R. W. Gilder, concerning it Gift of James T. Babb, 1962
    - 2 ALS to David A(lexander) Munro, Arlington, Mass., 1907 November, December
    - ALS to Jessie B(elle) Rittenhouse, Arlington, Mass., 1904 December 5
    - ALS to Mr. Scott, Geneva, Switzerland, 1890 June 26
    - ALS to Mr. Smith, Arlington, Mass., 1878 July 1
    - ALS to Mr. Williamson, Kennebunkport, Me.
      Williamson apparently member of firm that published Peter Budstone (1888)
  - TRUAX, RHODA (Box 29, Folder 1106)
    - 2 ALS to Godfrey F(rank) Singer, Brookline, Mass., [1932-1933]
      Letters removed from copies of her Hospital (1932) and Doctors carry the keys (1933), both with pres. inscrs.
      to Godfrey F. Singer
      From Blum Library
  - TRÜBNER AND CO. (Box 29, Folder 1107)
    - ALS to Franklin B(enjamin) Sanborn, London, Eng., 1881 May 14
      Concerning the works of Theodore Parker
  - TRUMBULL, JOHN, 1750-1831, 2 (Box 29, Folder 1108-1109)
    - ALS to Samuel Quincy, New Haven, 1773 July 22
    - ALS to Amherst D. Scovell, Hartford, Conn., 1827 October 25
      Purchased from the Torrington Library (with 7 others) fromYale Memorial fund, August. 15, 1960
  - TUCKERMAN, HENRY T. (HENRY THEODORE), 1813-1871, 3 (Box 29, Folder 1110-1112)
    - ALS to Mrs. Botta, [New York], 1864 February 24
      On 1st blank leaf of folder containing on 2d leaf a printed circular letter signed by John P(endleton) Kennedy and Alexander Bliss, Baltimore, February 5, 1864, concerning the Maryland State Fair fund for the sick and wounded soldiers of the national army
      Removed from: Za copy of his A sheaf of verse, 1864
    - ALS to J. T. Fields, New York, July 23
      Removed from: Za copy of his Characteristics, 2d ser., 1851
    - ALS to "My dear Friend," New York, 1849 December 29
    - ALS to "My dear Friend," 62 Clinton Place [New York?], undated
      Removed from: Za copy of his Selections [n. p., 187-?]
    - ALS to Ticknor and Fields, Newport, R. I., 1866 August 18
      Removed from: Za copy of his The criterion, New York, 1866 Gift of O. F. Aldis, 1911
    - ALS to MacKenzie, New York, 1868 April 18
      Removed from: Za copy of his Book of the artists, New York, 1867
    - ALS to N. C. Brooks, Boston, 1840 April 18
      Removed from: Za copy of his Isabel, Philadelphia, 1839
    - 5 ALS to E. P. Whipple, New York, 1848-1869
      Removed from: Za copies of his The optimist, New York, London, 1850; The collector, London [1868]; The life of Silas Talbot, New York, 1850; The rebellion, New York, 1861; Rambles, New York, 1841
    - ALS to Dr. John Wakefield Francis, Drybrook, Wednesday morning, undated
    - 3 ANS to Mrs. John Wakefield Francis, two without place or date; third from Newport, R. I., September 22
    - 3 ANS to Dr. Samuel Ward Francis, Newport, R. I., and New York, 1860-1871
    - ALS to Robert C(assie) Waterston, Philadelphia, Pa., 1832 June 16
      Gift of Fred T. Murphy, 1957